import { Question } from '../interfaces/question';

export const QUESTIONS: Question[] = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: 'What year was the very first model of the iPhone released?',
    answer: '2007',
    category: 'Science & Nature',
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: 'What’s the shortcut for the “copy” function on most computers?',
    answer: 'Ctrl C',
    category: 'Science & Nature',
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: 'What does “HTTP” stand for?',
    answer: 'HyperText Transfer Protocol',
    category: 'Science & Nature',
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question:
      'Google Chrome, Safari, Firefox and Explorer are different types of what?',
    answer: 'Web browsers',
    category: 'Science & Nature',
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: 'What was Twitter’s original name?',
    answer: 'Twttr',
    category: 'Science & Nature',
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: 'What is often seen as the smallest unit of memory?',
    answer: 'Kilobyte',
    category: 'Science & Nature',
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: 'In a website browser address bar, what does “www” stand for??',
    answer: 'World Wide Web',
    category: 'Science & Nature',
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: 'Which Williams sister has won more Grand Slam titles?',
    answer: 'Serena',
    category: 'Sports & Leisure',
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question:
      'Which Jamaican runner is an 11-time world champion and holds the record in the 100 and 200-meter race?',
    answer: 'Usain Bolt',
    category: 'Sports & Leisure',
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: 'Who was the first woman to win a Nobel Prize (in 1903)?',
    answer: 'Marie Curie',
    category: 'Science & Nature',
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: 'What part of the atom has no electric charge?',
    answer: 'Neutron',
    category: 'Science & Nature',
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: 'Which natural disaster is measured with a Richter scale?',
    answer: 'Earthquakes',
    category: 'Science & Nature',
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question:
      'What is the name of the thin, but long country that spans more than half of the western coast of South America?',
    answer: 'Chile',
    category: 'Geography',
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: 'Which American state is the largest (by area)?',
    answer: 'Alaska',
    category: 'Geography',
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: 'What is the name of the world’s longest river?',
    answer: 'Nile',
    category: 'Geography',
  },

  {
    id: 16,
    question:
      'What was the name of the group Justin Timberlake used to be part of?',
    answer: "N'SYNC",
    category: 'Entertainment',
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question: 'Who was the lead singer of the iconic ‘80s band, Culture Club?',
    answer: 'Boy George',
    category: 'Entertainment',
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: 'Which name is rapper Sean Combs better known by?',
    answer: 'P. Diddy',
    category: 'Entertainment',
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question: 'Which musical legend is Jay-Z married to?',
    answer: 'Beyonce',
    category: 'Entertainment',
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question: 'Which British girl group had a member by the name of Mel B?',
    answer: 'Spice Girls',
    category: 'Entertainment',
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question:
      'What was the name of the actor who played Jack Dawson in Titanic?',
    answer: 'Leonardo DiCaprio',
    category: 'Entertainment',
  },
];
